rohde-schwarz.com 2010-06-22

# Statement of Privacy (Rohde & Schwarz International)

### Statement of Privacy / Data Protection

Rohde & Schwarz is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. This statement informs you about the information practices at Rohde & Schwarz and its partner companies and on Rohde & Schwarz websites, including what type of information is gathered and tracked, how the information is used and with whom the information is shared.

In general, you can visit and browse through the Rohde & Schwarz websites without revealing any personal information.

There are times, however, when Rohde & Schwarz and/or its partner companies may need information from you. You may choose to give us personal information, such as your name and (e-mail) address that may be required to correspond with you, provide you with a subscription, or respond to an order. Rohde & Schwarz and/or its partner companies shall be happy to respond to you immediately. For these purposes, it will be necessary to process your personal information at Rohde & Schwarz, and it may become necessary to transfer your personal information to the relevant partner companies of Rohde & Schwarz.

Once you have disclosed your personal information, Rohde & Schwarz and its partner companies shall process this information exclusively for the purposes of pursuing the business relationship with you. Rohde & Schwarz may appoint its partner companies to provide limited services on behalf of Rohde & Schwarz, including but not limited to answering your questions about products, services, processing event registration or perform orders. Rohde & Schwarz shall provide those companies only with such information as they will need for the subject matter and shall prohibit them from using the information for any other purpose.

Your personal information shall be treated strictly in accordance with the applicable national data protection provisions. Within the **E** uropean **U** nion (EU), a standardized Data Protection level applies, including the transfer of personal information within the EU. The transfer of personal information in a country that is not a member of the EU must be accompanied by an agreement that secures the same level of data protection in the country of destination as in the EU. However, no such transfer shall take place without express prior notice.

Furthermore, Rohde & Schwarz has implemented appropriate technical and organizational measures, such as using encryption for transmission, in order to keep your information secure, accurate, current and complete.

Once you are registered at Rohde & Schwarz, you may wish to check your personal information processed at Rohde & Schwarz. To do so, please [send an e-mail to the webmaster](mailto:webmaster@rohde-schwarz.com?subject=Statement%20of%20Privacy:%20check%20personal%20information%20disclosed).

Should you wish to have your personal information corrected or completed, please feel free to [send your request to Rohde & Schwarz](mailto:webmaster@rohde-schwarz.com?subject=Statement%20of%20Privacy:%20correct%20personal%20information).

Rohde & Schwarz shall comply with your request immediately.

Your personal information shall be processed for the time and to the extent necessary in respect of the business relationship with you. Thereafter, your personal information shall be blocked/deleted as required by law.

Nevertheless, you are entitled to demand blocking/deletion of your personal data at any time. However, you should be aware that blocking/deletion of your personal information will prevent Rohde & Schwarz and its partner companies from having any further contact with you.

Rohde & Schwarz may collect information anonymously from visits to its websites in order to provide you with improved service. Rohde & Schwarz may keep track of the domains from which you visit and also analyze your activities on the websites of Rohde & Schwarz, but in a way that keeps the information anonymously. This anonymous information is analyzed and used only at an aggregate level to help Rohde & Schwarz to realize trends and patterns. None of this information is reviewed at an individual level.

Rohde & Schwarz may collect the anonymous information through the use of various technologies, including cookies. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, and which may then be stored on your computer system. You can set your browser to inform you when a cookie is received, thus enabling you to decide whether to accept or refuse it.

The Rohde & Schwarz websites may contain links to other websites. Rohde & Schwarz cannot assume any responsibility whatsoever, neither for the privacy practices nor the content of such websites.
